（竜介(りゅうすけ)：英語）〈ああ 分かった〉
I never dreamed before
I'm gonna knock the door
〈契約関係はすべて
そっちに任せるよ〉
into the world of perfect free
〈ああ〉
（竜介）〈えっ？〉
〈BECK(ベック)って
バンド名はマズい？〉
(You ain't no lonely!)
You're gonna say I'm lying
〈じゃあ アメリカ受け
しそうな名前—〉
〈何かつけてくれよ〉
I'm gonna get the chance
〈datは早急に送るぜ
よろしく〉
I thought a chance is far from me
(You ain't no lonely!)
I was made to hit in America
（千葉(ちば)）お～い 竜介～！
(I was made to hit in America)
いるか～？
I was made to hit in America
（千葉）
ええっ!? 海外デビュー!?
You are the sun, you are the star
（平(たいら)）こんな簡単に？
いや… ラッキーだな
(To me, forever)
いや そんなに
期待できないと思うぜ
You are the sun, you are the star
アメリカっつっても 超マイナーな
インディーレーベルだからな
(To me, forever)
I was made to hit in America
(I was made to hit in America)
Yeah...Yeah...Okay. I'll leave
everything about the contract to you.
Yeah...
What? The band name
"Beck" is no good there?
Then you name something
works good in U.S.
Yeah. I'll send you the DAT
as soon as possible.
Okay. 'Bye...
Hey, Ryusuke! Are you here?
What?! An overseas debut?
ああ えっと…
アルビンおじさん
So easily? I mean...we're lucky.
名刺の人ね
（竜介）でも 社長の熱意
みたいなのは感じるんだ
No, I don't think
we should expect too much.
BECKのこと 今まで聴いた
日本のバンドの中で 最高だってさ
True, it's the U.S.,
but this is a very obscure label.
Yeah...Um...Mr. Albin...
The guy with the name card, right?
ムフフ フフフ…
アメリカ!! 金髪美人！
ムフッ ムフフフ…
But, I can feel the enthusiasm in him.
He says Beck is the best band
he's heard in Japan.
（竜介）ハァ…
（平）おっ
Hmm...
America! Blonde beauties.
（竜介）海外のほうが
合ってんのかなあ 俺たち
I wonder if we'd fit in better overseas...
アメリカか
America?
"Live 17
'Three Days'"
（高野(たかの)）ほらよっ
Here you go.
（コユキ）
あっ ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
（高野）ふん
（店員）お客さんに
あんなに お礼 言われるなんて
Unusual for a customer be so thankful...
（高野）うん ホントにな
Yeah...I haven't seen a customer
so happy in a long time.
あんなに うれしそうなお客
久しぶりに見たよ
（コユキの母）
幸雄～ うるさいよ！
Yukio! You're too loud!
（コユキ）
あっ ああ ごめんごめん
Oh...I'm sorry!
えっと ボリューム ボリューム…
Let's see...Volume...volume...Okay.
よし
（サク）へえ 朝までねえ
Oh? Till morning?
Yeah. It's completely different
from a Gretsch so it's a lot of fun!
グレッチと 全然
タイプが違うからさあ—
弾いてて めちゃくちゃ
面白いんだ
A Telecaster?
テレキャスかあ
うん さすがに バイト
１回 休んじゃったけどね
Mm-hmm...I even took
a day off my job for this.
そっか バイト
クビになんないようにな
I see...
-Be careful you don't lose your job!
-Uh-huh...
（コユキ）おう
ああっ！ あの子！
Oh! That girl!
（鬼形(きがた)）うーむ
（コユキ）んんっ ハァ ハァ
あー！ やっぱり！
-Oh...It is!
-Huh?!
（益岡(ますおか)）ええっ!?
Ooh...Ouch...
いった～ うう…
（コユキ）ああ… 大丈夫？
Are you all right?
I-I guess so...
（益岡）なっ 何とか…
き 君…
You...Aren't you the girl
working at the donut shop?
確か ドーナツ屋で働いている…
田中… 君？
Tanaka...kun?
ええ？
（益岡）アハッ
"Health Room"
（コユキ）何で 俺の名前…
How did you know my name?
だって いつも
怒られてますよね
Well, you're always getting scolded.
Oh, is that why? How embarrassing!
ああっ そっか
カッコ悪～ エヘヘ
Okay. I'm done.
（養護教諭）ほら 終わったよ
It's nothing serious, but be
careful for two or three days.
大したことないけど
２～３日は おとなしくしてね
All right.
は～い
（コユキ）あそこの店
人使いが荒いんだ
The employees aren't treated
very well at that shop.
That's why the worker
turnover is so great.
だから 入った人が すぐ
辞めてっちゃうんだよ
Tanaka-kun...Can you play the guitar?
田中君 ギター 弾けるんですか？
えっ 弾けるんでしょ？
Huh? You can play, can't you?
No. Not at all.
ううん 全然
あ 俺 このギターケース
軽音楽部の部室で見たけど
I...This guitar case...
I saw it in the Light Music Club room.
うん 部長さんにどなられて
３日で辞めました
Yeah...The club leader yelled at me,
so I quit after three days.
Your name?
君…
Oh! I'm Hiromi Masuoka.
あ 私 益岡弘美です
（コユキ）
ま～す～おか ひろみ～
Hiromi Masuoka...Hiromi Masuoka...
Hiromi Masuoka...
ますおか ひろみ～
ますおか～
Hiromi Masuoka, Hiromi Masuoka...
ますおか ひろみ
Hiromi Masuoka...
ますおか ひろみ～
Wow...
Why, you're good, Tanaka-kun.
へえ～ 田中君 うまいねえ
What's that song you just sang?
今の歌 何ていうんですか？
It's a song called Face by Beck.
BECKの「FACE(フェイス)」って曲なんだ
I'm impressed, Tanaka-kun.
すごいね 田中君
ありがと
Thank you. This guitar seems to be fine.
あ ギターは無事みたいだね
（コユキ）あ じゃあ
今度 僕が教えてあげようか
-Shall I give you lessons, then?
-Yes. Thank you!
（益岡）あっ！ お願いします
Thank you for letting me use
your White Falcon all this time.
ホワイトファルコン
今まで貸してくれて—
ありがとうございました
Mm-hmm...Let me know anytime
you want to use it.
（斎藤(さいとう)）フウッ また
使いたくなったら 言いなさい
You can borrow it anytime.
いつでも貸してあげるから
All right.
（コユキ）はい
（斎藤）ああ～ もしもし
こっちはいつでも出られますよ
Uh...hello...I'm ready anytime.
What about you, Momo-chan?
桃(もも)ちゃんは どう？
I see. Then, see you as usual
in front of the dog...Bye...
あ そっか じゃあいつもの
犬の前でねっ じゃっ
Momoko-sensei!
（コユキ）桃子(ももこ)先生？
Actually, word got out that I once
worked for a week at a cabaret club
（桃子）実はね 昔—
ランパブで １週間
バイトしたことが—
thanks to a former student.
卒業生の告発で バレちゃって—
It became a problem among the staff
when they found out I had kept it a secret.
それを秘密にしてたのが
職員室で問題になったの
It was such a shock.
I was really troubled over it.
すごいショックで
いろいろ悩んだんだ
I tried going to various seminars...
いろんなセミナーにも出たし
そんなとき…
-And then...
-I became her confidant.
僕が相談に乗ってあげたんだよ
No one understands better than I do
about the entertainment business.
風俗関係には 誰よりも
理解があるからねえ～
Yeah, better than anyone...
ああっ 誰よりもね
Ouch!
Our relationship is still platonic,
so don't go saying anything unnecessary.
桃ちゃんとは まだ
男と女の関係じゃないんだよ
だから 余分なことは
言わないように！
Mm...
So long, Koyuki-kun!
じゃあねっ！ コユキ君
Kenichi Saito, 44...Currently dashing
through the roads of his youth.
（コユキ）斎藤研一 44歳
ただいま 青春街道 ばく進中
I haven't seen you
at work recently, Masuoka-san.
（コユキ）最近 益岡さん
バイト先で 見かけないんだけど
The truth is, I made a mistake
that was a big blow to the shop,
私 実は お店に
大打撃を与えるミス 犯して—
and so they fired me...
クビになっちゃったんです～
But I'm really excited
about the new club I joined!
でも 今は
新しく入った部活に—
すごく燃えてるんですよ！
Oh...
So long...
じゃあ！ フフッ
（コユキ）ふん
Grade 10-B, Hiromi Masuoka...
１年２組 益岡弘美かあ
Huh? You know her?
えっ 知ってんの？
（サク）フフフフ
とっくにチェック済みさ
Sure. I've checked her out.
Ohh...
When she was in intermediate school,
she had a good record.
中学時代には まずまずの
成績を残してるんだよ
Oh?
へえ～
I wonder if she wouldn't
come to our live show...
益岡さん 俺たちのライブ
来ないかなあ？
I wonder...
どうかな～
Hiromi, why don't you take
a break? You must be thirsty.
（部員）
弘美 少し 休めば？
のど 渇いたでしょ？ はい
（益岡）ありがと！
-Here.
-Thanks!
Okay! I'll invite her later.
よし！ あとで誘ってみよう
Huh?
"Belle Ame-First National Live House Tour"
"Expectations High for New Band"
Beck...eat it.
Hello? Hey, Mr. Albin...
Hey, how's our CD going?
ハロー
〈あぁ アルビンさんか〉
〈どうだい 俺たちのＣＤは〉
What?!
〈え？〉
（ヨシト）兄貴！
兄貴の優勝におかげで—
Brother...It's because of your victory...
that I am now able to walk!
俺 歩けるようになったんだ！
（兄）フッ バカだな お前
Huh...Don't be silly...
兄貴!! ううっ
Brother...Brother!!
兄貴～!!
（千葉）ふ～ん
うおっ！ あちゃ～
（サク）ありがとうございましたっ
Thank you very much!
Hmm...
（料理人）
何 やっとんじゃ コラァ～
What are you doing, kid?!
すいません！
I'm sorry!
...feel totally loose
This crazy, crazy world
You just have to Stage Dive or Die
Mind blower, a shower of sweat
Run towards a new world, my life
Those who seek it will be rewarded
Pass the hot shot
Keep on coming, come on!
Blow your mind
何 やってんだよ！ コユキ
What are you doing, Koyuki?!
（サク）おなか空いたね
（コユキ）ああ
Boy, am I hungry.
Yeah...
（千葉）なあなあ
ラーメン 食って帰ろうぜ
Let's have some ramen noodles
before we head home.
（平）うん いいね
Hmm...Good idea.
（竜介）チッ また ラーメンかよ
Ramen again?!
（真帆(まほ)）よお！
Yo!
Huh?
（真帆）お待たせー！
Sorry to keep you waiting.
えっ 竜介君は？
Where's Ryusuke-kun?
用事ができたんで お前行けって
券 くれたんだあ
Something came up so he gave me
the tickets and told me to go.
"'Three Days' Directed by Jim Walsh-
No.1 hit in U.S.!!"
Why are you always like this?!
What can I do? Our way
of living is too different.
Right. That's it, then.
Maybe...
I still love you.
Me, too.
Take care.
（コユキ）この映画
ちょっと難解だけど—
-The movie was a little hard to understand,
but the characters were so real
-It's been a while. How's life?
登場人物が生き生きとしてて
映画が終わるとき—
-The movie was a little hard to understand,
but the characters were so real
-I'm alive...
-that when the movie ended,
I felt a little sad leaving them.
-It's a tough world.
彼らと別れるのが
少し さびしかった
-That when the movie ended,
I felt a little sad leaving them.
-Yeah.
（真帆）ジム・ウォルシュ
Jim Walsh...This director is a genius!
この監督 天才だよ
うん！ 面白かった
全然 眠くなんなかったもん
Yeah. It was interesting.
Why, I didn't get sleepy at all.
この映画が好評で
ダイブリのツアームービー…
I hear this movie is such a hit that
Dying Breed's concert tour movie
日米同時公開なんだってさ
is going to be released
simultaneously in the U.S. And Japan.
へえ～ ツアームービー
Oh? Their concert tour movie?
ハーイ
Hi!
（ヨシト：英語）
〈真帆 土曜空いてない？〉
Maho, I'm going to have dinner with Morita
and Eguchi-san, whom I'm playing with.
〈共演の森田(もりた)君や江口(えぐち)さんと—〉
Are you free on Saturday?
〈メシ食うんだけどさ〉
（真帆：英語）〈へぇ いいね〉
That's nice, but I've got a Beck's live.
〈でも土曜は無理だな
BECKのライブがあるから〉
江口さんとメシだってさ～
He says he's having
dinner with Eguchi-san!
Huh?!
〈また誘って〉
Call me again the next time.
-What?! You're not gonna say you...
-Bye!
〈じゃっ！〉
さっ 何か食べに行こうぜ
Now...Let's go and get something to eat.
Okay!
（千葉）ええっ マジ!?
What? Really!
（竜介）ああ 何気に
売れてるらしいんだよな
Yeah. They seem to be selling pretty well.
俺たちの歌が
（千葉）んん んん…
Our song...
日本のバンドじゃ
異例のことらしい
Seems it's unusual for a Japanese band.
あの社長 やり手だよ
That president gets things done.
（千葉）えっと～
アルペンさんだっけ？
Uh...His name was Albin-san, was it?
どしたの？
What's wrong?
（千葉）どしたの？
やっときゃ よかった 印税契約
I should've signed
the contract for royalties.
何だよ
何枚 売れても 同じかよ～
What? You mean it doesn't matter
how many copies they sell?!
（平）それじゃあ いくら売れても
（竜介）いってえ
-So no matter how many
copies they sell...
-Ouch!
What...What? Aargh!
Spice!
Check, check, check, check...
Uh! Uh!
Blow your mind
Squeeze your sweat yeah
Squeeze your sweat
Large lips in the motion
Trying to keep blaming on
As I say reason I'm late on
Find you turning
Laughing and smiling
まだ 耳がキーンとしてるけど
すごく よかった！
My ears are still ringing...
but it was really great.
（コユキ）ホント？
うれしいな ねえ サク？
Really? I'm glad.
Right, Saku?
Yeah, for real.
ホント ホント
（益岡の友人）
めっちゃ ヤバイよね
It was awesome!
And the crowd was huge!
それに あんなに
お客さん多いし！
少しずつだけど
お客さん 増えてるんだ
Little by little we've been
getting bigger crowds.
益岡さんも また来てよ
Come again, Masuoka-san.
-I will!
-Hmph!
（益岡）はい！
（真帆）フンッ
（男性１）BECK 今度
マーキーでやるらしい
I hear Beck's playing
at the Marquee next.
（男性）うっそ すげーじゃん
No way...That's terrific!
（女性）
どんどん 出世していくなあ
They're really gaining in popularity.
Say, didn't that guy look
like Yoshito Morozumi?
（女性）あっ ねえねえ 今の
諸積(もろづみ)ヨシトに似てなかった？
No way...Really?
（女性１）えっ ウソ ほんまに？
（女性）ああいう人
こんなとこに いないって
He wouldn't be in a place like this...
Hmph! They're nothing but
a little-known amateur band!
（ヨシト）フンッ あんなのただの
無名のアマチュアバンドじゃねえか
社長から留守電が残ってたよ
There was a message from the president.
BECKのＣＤ
追加生産するってさ
They're going to print
more copies of our CD.
アメリカで 俺らの音楽が
鳴ってるのか
So our music is playing in America?
Yeah...
（平）なあ
（竜介）あん？
-Say...
-Huh?
Can you tell me the story?
そろそろ 話してくれないか
Where did you get it?
どこで手に入れた？
I stole it.
盗んだんだよ
車上荒らし？
You broke into cars?!
（竜介）フンッ
We had time on our hands,
so Eddy and I often did it.
ヒマだったんで エディと
よくやったんだ
それで あのヤバイ車に
あたったんだ
And then we came upon that hot car.
What surprised us more was...
（竜介）
それ以上に ビックリしたのは…
That's Lucille!
（エディ・リー：英語）
〈ルシールだ〉
What? This car is no good, Eddy.
（竜介）〈何だって？〉
〈ヤバイよ この車〉
No, look! This is Sonny Boy Waters' guitar.
（エディ）
〈あんま 知られてないけど—〉
He's a blues guitarist.
Even Eric Clapton respects him.
〈エリック・クラプトンも
尊敬してる—〉
〈伝説のブルースギタリスト—〉
〈サニーボーイウォーターズの
ギターなんだ〉
He's a legend.
Sonny Boy?
（竜介）〈サニーボーイ〉
Serial Number...8-3001...
（エディ）〈シリアルナンバー
８ 3001〉
Dude, that's it!
〈間違いない！〉
Come on! Let's go!
（竜介）
〈エディ 早く逃げようぜ〉
See, Sonny Boy and this guy were
（エディ）〈サニーボーイと
ある男がナイトクラブで—〉
fighting over this woman
called Lucille in a night club.
〈ルシールという
女を巡って争ったんだ〉
And the guy shot Sonny Boy
right on the stage.
〈そして逆上した男が 翌日〉
〈ライブ中の
サニーボーイを撃ち殺した〉
You mean, during the play?
（竜介）〈演奏中にか〉
The guitar's been called Lucille
ever since then.
（エディ）〈その事件以来—〉
〈ルシールと呼ばれているのが
このギターだ〉
That's insane...
（竜介）〈マジかよ〉
Okay. Let's get outta here. Come on.
（エディ）〈さ 逃げるぞ〉
〈早く来い〉
Hey, Ray!
（エディ）ヘイ レイ！
I kind of like this guitar.
（竜介）〈俺 このギターが
妙に気に入った〉
What?
（エディ）〈何？〉
I'll be the legend after Sonny Boy.
〈俺 サニーボーイの
伝説を受け継ぐよ〉
-Huh?
And that's when I met up with Beck.
（竜介）そんときに
あいつと出会ったんだ
I found out later...
（竜介）あとで知ったんだ
The car belonged to
someone really dangerous.
すごくヤバイ男の車だって
And now he's searching frantically
for Beck and Lucille.
そしてそいつが今 血眼で
ベックとルシールを捜し回ってる
"Director Jim Walsh's Newest Film-
Dying Breed's Road Tour Movie"
Hey! We have a group in. Your break is up.
（店長）お～い
団体客だぞ 休憩 終わりだ
Okay...I'll be right there!
はーい！ 今 行きます
Another minute
Feelin' so fine
You turn the freeze
into warm light
Had a premonition
I've been waitin' ever since
My world comin' down
It's got me spinnin' 'round
If you really wanna fly
you gotta let go
Simply the most
big sensation
(once you're here you won't go back)
She's really pretty
One-eyed vision
(lose the fear it don't come back)
Little sister showed me
Really took me for a ride
My world comin' down
(once you're here you won't go back)
(lose the fear it don't come back)
-I'm Atsushi.
-I'm Eriko.
（アツシ）アツシです
（エナポゥ）エナポゥです
-Together we are...
-The Chipped Teapot...Boing...
（アツシ）２人あわせて
（エナポゥ）ハゲちょびんです
"Live 18 'Leon Sykes'"
-Together we are...
-The Chipped Teapot...Boing...
（２人）ぼよよよ～ん
"Live 18 'Leon Sykes'"
Bonny Jump is doing a live show.
（エナポゥ）
ＰＯＮＩ-ＣＡＭＰが
ライブをやります
"Live 18 'Leon Sykes'"
-Be sure to come...
...and watch.
（２人）来てね～
（千葉）来てね